<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Elect Your Adventure</title>
  
  <subtitle>Stories Written by Popular Vote</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://JonHolt.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-06-19T05:30:15.381Z</updated>
  <id>https://JonHolt.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Holt</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Reaction</title>
    <link href="https://JonHolt.github.io/2018/06/18/Reaction/"/>
    <id>https://JonHolt.github.io/2018/06/18/Reaction/</id>
    <published>2018-06-19T04:20:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-19T05:30:15.381Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This post was written in response to the following writing prompt from reddit:</em> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/8s0t2k/wp_after_paris_was_razed_by_an_alien_weapon_the/?utm_content=title&amp;utm_medium=user&amp;utm_source=reddit" target="_blank" rel="noopener">After Paris was razed by an alien weapon the world awaits the imminent invasion. What humanity doesn’t know is that it was just a stray shot of a war fought millenia ago</a></p><p>Many historians suspect to this day that a third world war would have erupted on October 17th 2021, or shortly thereafter. Tensions were high, as trade wars had been waging between the worlds superpowers for some time, and a few of them were starting to realize that a war of trade would not get them all that they wanted. A summit had been called for the leaders of the world to meet in Paris on that day, in order to discuss the situation and hopefully back down from the brink of mutual destruction. But the third world war never started, and not because the summit was a success. Rather it was because of the opposite, for that was the day that thunder struck Paris. Some call it the shot that was <em>actually</em> heard around the world.</p><p>We still don’t know who fired at us, but what scientists were able to determine that a 20 kilogram projectile had fallen on the city at a speed of 1% - 1.3% of the speed of light. The weapon was not a nuke, however it struck with enough force to cause an explosion three times more devastating than the nuclear explosion over Hiroshima at the end of World War II. Three things were made clear to all of humanity that day: we are not alone, whoever is out there has better guns than us, and those guns are pointed in our direction.</p><p>World leader’s stopped meeting in person after that, for it was clear the enemy was looking for chances to destabilize the Earth’s governments. However despite this, international cooperation reached an all time high. Threat of imminent destruction is apparently a good motivator for working together. China and India immediately began developing an early warning system. As long as the enemy’s weapon traveled slower than light, it could be detected <em>before</em> impact. In tandem, the US and Russia began working on railguns of our own. Yes, for firing back at our as yet unseen enemies, but also we developed guns that could be targeted and fired quickly enough to intercept an incoming round in the time between its detection at the edge of our solar system and its impact on Earth.</p><p>For decades humanity continued its rapid advance in space faring tech, united by the terror imposed by one precision strike from a relativistic weapon. As soon as we were able, we started sending people to live in other star systems, for the best way for a species to survive a planet busting weapon is to not live entirely on one planet. And as the centuries wore on, interstellar travel became normal. The human race spread like wildfire to every habitable world they could find.</p><p>Yet not once, in all of this time preparing for the fight of their lives, did the human race encounter another hint of the enemy that struck them so long ago. All this progress, and all of humanity’s preparation for war did not come without doubts. There were always those who questioned: Why didn’t the attackers follow up when they had such a clear advantage? What advantage could possibly be gained by destroying one city and then leaving? After all these years of searching for the bastards that knocked us down, why haven’t we been able to even hear a hint of radio signal from them?</p><p>Some factions began to form and jockey for power in the Human Galactic Empire. Some believed that the invading force had been eliminated by some benevolent protector, as yet unseen simply because they did not wish to be. Others were of the opinion that the attack had been a wake up call, designed to stop humanity from in-fighting and unite them in one glorious push for the stars. Still others decided that the original attack had been faked, a conspiracy by a hidden world government in order to weaken the individual nations and solidify its position of power.</p><p>Of course you should always expect the human race to squabble over the dumbest things. So naturally we should have expected that another war would be unavoidable. And here we are, Humanity’s third great war. It has been long delayed, but also greatly inflated in scale. For the quarrel that would once have scoured the surface of a single planet now rages out of control across the entirety of human-occupied space.</p><p>“Yeah captain, thanks for the history lesson, but what’s that got to do with us?”</p><p>The ship’s captain smiled grimly. “I’m just wondering if the shot that united us for so long might have come from something as stupid as a gunner failing to double check his firing solution before pulling the trigger 10,000 years ago.”</p><p>The crewman flushed as the captain’s point hit home. “I’m sorry sir. It won’t happen again.”</p><p>“See that it doesn’t.”</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was written in response to the following writing prompt from reddit:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Reddit WP" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/categories/Reddit-WP/"/>
    
    
      <category term="sci-fi" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/tags/sci-fi/"/>
    
      <category term="reddit" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/tags/reddit/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Check Up</title>
    <link href="https://JonHolt.github.io/2018/06/12/Check-Up/"/>
    <id>https://JonHolt.github.io/2018/06/12/Check-Up/</id>
    <published>2018-06-12T13:40:55.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-12T14:00:24.792Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“Try your best to describe to me what you’re feeling.” The doctor said while shining a light in Sarah’s eye. Sarah flinched away from the light and tried to blink the flashing after-image into submission.</p><p>“It’s just a little headache mostly, nothing a baby aspirin won’t fix.” She began, “Otherwise just a little bit of déjà vu and some minor disorientation that I’m sure is caused by the headache.”</p><p>“Look here.” the doctor directed before cruelly shining his light in her other eye. While Sarah was confident she had been in good shape to fly before this exam, she wasn’t so sure that would be the case when this doctor was finished blinding her. The doctor made a note on his clipboard. “Can you elaborate on the disorientation?”</p><p>“It’s not that bad really,” Sarah said, once again blinking frantically to clear her vision. “It just took me a bit longer than normal to find some of the controls. It’s like the configuration of the control panel was… slightly different from what I’m used to. Also, I can’t get over the feeling that I’ve been through this before.”</p><p>The doctor had strapped an inflatable cuff around her arm and was in the process of pumping it up to check her blood pressure. “What, this exam?” If he was joking that would be the first hint of bedside manner had seen in the man, though his face showed no hint of a joke.</p><p>“No. <em>This</em> is all new.” Something in Sarah’s voice made it clear she’d rather it weren’t happening at all. She caught herself thinking back on the launch when she didn’t have to get a medical exam; or forward, or… laterally? She wasn’t really sure. She’d rather be experiencing that glorious launch that she remembered so clearly, despite the fact that she was certain now that it had never happened. “I mean the launch. I remember launching, reaching orbit, making a joke about a file cabinet, and even punching in the coordinates for a quick jump to the moon and back.”</p><p>“You remember that far ahead?” this actually got the doctor to look up from his clipboard. “That’s a bit unusual for déjà vu, it’s usually just that you remember what you’re currently doing as being familiar. It’s never actually a ‘memory’ of the future.” He stopped to think for a few silent seconds. “How was your trip to the moon then, the one you remember?”</p><p>“Well I didn’t make it that far…” Sarah drifted off trying to remember beyond the first jump. “I remember punching in the coordinates, and then counting down, and then I was here about to take off again only with a splitting headache.”</p><p>“I thought you said it was nothing a baby aspirin wouldn’t fix.”</p><p>“Right, yeah. That’s what I meant.” Sarah didn’t even look a little guilty about getting caught in her lie.</p><p>“Uh huh….” The doctor was back to his clipboard. At that moment, there was a knock at the exam room’s door. The doctor set down his clipboard and opened the door a crack. “What is it?”</p><p>“We need Captain Meyer in the control room. We’re picking up a transponder signal from… <em>something</em> in orbit around the moon. It’s the signal from her ship.”</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;“Try your best to describe to me what you’re feeling.” The doctor said while shining a light in Sarah’s eye. Sarah flinched away from the
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Look Before You Leap" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/categories/Look-Before-You-Leap/"/>
    
    
      <category term="sci-fi" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/tags/sci-fi/"/>
    
      <category term="space travel" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/tags/space-travel/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>déjà vu</title>
    <link href="https://JonHolt.github.io/2018/06/05/deja-vu/"/>
    <id>https://JonHolt.github.io/2018/06/05/deja-vu/</id>
    <published>2018-06-05T21:47:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-05T21:58:13.139Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“…Captain? Captain Meyer! Can you read me?”</p><p>Sarah awoke to a splitting headache. “Oh god…” she muttered as her double-vision of the capsule slowly merged into one. “What the h-”</p><p>“How’re you feeling Sarah?” the concern in Thomas’ voice was apparent. “Do we need to scrub the launch?”</p><p>“Scrub the launch? Didn’t we…” <em>already launch?</em>  Sarah bit her tongue. <em>Of course I haven’t launched yet, otherwise I wouldn’t be experiencing gravity.</em> She looked out of the window of her capsule.</p><p><strong>Blue sky.</strong></p><p>“Repeat that last Captain, you cut out.”</p><p>“Didn’t we talk about this Thomas? This launch is too important to scrub over a little headache. I’ll be fine.” <em>Will I?</em></p><p>“Understood Captain, but let us know if it gets worse.”</p><p>“I will.” She was answering herself more than Thomas.</p><p>“Then let’s finish up this preflight check and get this countdown rolling.”</p><p>Over the next five minutes Sarah fumbled awkwardly through the last of the systems checks. Not only was she having trouble focusing due to the headache, she also couldn’t shake the feeling that something wasn’t right, that she’d done this before. Then there was the fact that she couldn’t find half of the controls in the cockpit without help. She could swear they were organized differently last time. <em>Last time? There was no last time. This is the first launch.</em></p><p>“I’m not sure we should proceed with the launch.” Thomas’ voice came hesitantly over the coms, “I’m recommending we postpone the launch until we can verify the pilot is capable of completing the mission.”</p><p>“It’ll be fine.” Sarah insisted, “The autopilot will be doing all the work anyway.”</p><p>“…Sarah, there is no autopilot. We took that system out when we discovered it was interfering with the warp drive in the unmanned tests.”</p><p><strong>Silence</strong></p><p>“Hold on Captain Meyer, we’re awaiting a medical opinion on whether you’re okay to launch.”</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;“…Captain? Captain Meyer! Can you read me?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah awoke to a splitting headache. “Oh god…” she muttered as her double-vision of th
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Look Before You Leap" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/categories/Look-Before-You-Leap/"/>
    
    
      <category term="sci-fi" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/tags/sci-fi/"/>
    
      <category term="space travel" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/tags/space-travel/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Partial Success</title>
    <link href="https://JonHolt.github.io/2018/05/29/Partial-Success/"/>
    <id>https://JonHolt.github.io/2018/05/29/Partial-Success/</id>
    <published>2018-05-29T23:29:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-05-30T00:29:05.230Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A heavy silence fell over the mission control center for approximately 1.3 seconds between the time Captain Meyer’s transponder signal disappeared from the main display, up to the collective sigh of relief when it appeared again at the exact coordinates specified. A cheer went up among the engineers monitoring the telemetry data.</p><p>“Alright, alright! Quiet down! There will be plenty of time to celebrate later.” That was Remi Ashton, the ground commander for this test flight. “Thomas, ask her for a status report.”</p><p>“Captain Meyer, we’re reading that you’ve arrived at precisely the correct coordinates. How was the trip?”</p><p>An excited hubbub persisted in the room, despite the order to quiet down. A few engineers around the edges of the room were still chatting happily about the ramifications of human faster than light travel. Discussions ranged from excitement about the future of exploration in and around the solar system, to jealousy that Captain Meyer was the first to try it. </p><p>But the conversations, the bravado, and the smiles, all began to fade quickly as the expected 2.6 second transmission time passed without a response from the Captain. </p><p>“Captain, please respond, are you alright?” Thomas was always good at keeping the strain out of his voice when he was stressed. Perhaps that’s how he got the job as capcom. </p><p>Ashton turned to one of the controllers who was monitoring telemetry. “She could be hurt, bring up the camera feed of the cockpit.” </p><p>Another 2.6 seconds passed in an absence of sound somehow even more crushing than the moment following the jump. </p><p>“We’re getting the video feed now sir.” A window popped up on the main screen of the command center. The video showed the cockpit of Captain Meyer’s vessel in perfect working order, with one exception; The captain herself was missing.</p><p>“Will <em>somebody</em> please tell me where the hell Captain Meyer went?”</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;A heavy silence fell over the mission control center for approximately 1.3 seconds between the time Captain Meyer’s transponder signal di
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Look Before You Leap" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/categories/Look-Before-You-Leap/"/>
    
    
      <category term="sci-fi" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/tags/sci-fi/"/>
    
      <category term="space travel" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/tags/space-travel/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Look Before You Leap</title>
    <link href="https://JonHolt.github.io/2018/05/22/Look%20Before%20You%20Leap/"/>
    <id>https://JonHolt.github.io/2018/05/22/Look Before You Leap/</id>
    <published>2018-05-22T18:58:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-05-29T23:29:49.733Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Captain Sarah Meyer took a moment to relish the familiar feeling of weightlessness as the thrust cut out at the end of her orbital insertion burn. She smiled down at the brilliant blue Earth below  her.</p><p>“I gotta say Houston,” she began with a hint of mischief in her voice, “this thing flies like a file cabinet.”</p><p>“I’d like to see you fit humanity’s first ever hyperdrive into a file ca-”</p><p>“Would the engineers please leave capsule communication to the capsule communicator?” Thomas was on capcom today. “I’m sorry to hear that sitting in the pilot seat while autopilot took you into orbit was too much strain on your piloting skills Sarah. What’s your status?”</p><p>“Green across the board Houston” Sarah replied, “I’m reading that I’ve reached the target orbit, and the drive status is ready. Can you confirm?”</p><p>“Yes we’re seeing the same readings down here. Remember now, no new variables. We’re just running the same test that ten drones have already done before you. I want the only change here to be the fact that you’re driving. Jump to the programmed coordinates near the moon and report back when you get there, got it?”</p><p>“Understood Houston.” The first human being to ever jump to hyperspace grinned like a child in an ice cream shop as she input her destination into the jump computer and placed her thumb on the button to activate the hyperspace engine. “Jumping in 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.”</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;Captain Sarah Meyer took a moment to relish the familiar feeling of weightlessness as the thrust cut out at the end of her orbital insert
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Look Before You Leap" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/categories/Look-Before-You-Leap/"/>
    
    
      <category term="sci-fi" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/tags/sci-fi/"/>
    
      <category term="space travel" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/tags/space-travel/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <link href="https://JonHolt.github.io/2018/05/14/Introduction/"/>
    <id>https://JonHolt.github.io/2018/05/14/Introduction/</id>
    <published>2018-05-15T02:40:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2018-05-22T17:31:11.970Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my blog! My name is Jonathan. The purpose of this blog is for me to get some practice with creative writing, and for you to (hopefully) get some entertainment out of it. Please read the rest of this post to get the backround on why this blog exists, and how it will operate. Or if that sounds boring to you I’ve provided this handy tl;dr.</p><h3 id="TL-DR"><a href="#TL-DR" class="headerlink" title="TL;DR"></a>TL;DR</h3><ul><li>Read the latest post of the blog, which will be on the home page.</li><li>Vote in the comments on what should happen next.</li><li>Repeat one week later.</li><li>Sometimes there will be a bonus story that my brother made me write.</li><li>Stories will be organized by category.</li></ul><a id="more"></a><p>Before starting this blog, my brother and I decided to practice our creative writing by having weekly “story challenges” where we find a writing prompt online and write stories for them over the course of a week. At the end of the week we’re supposed to share our stories with each other and pick a new prompt. We started about a year ago, we’ve done somewhere around… four challenges, and I’ve shown my brother only one of my stories (all my fault).</p><p>This year of failure has taught me some things about myself though: </p><ul><li>I’m great at outlining story ideas from start to finish.</li><li>I’m less great at actually writing and filling in the details of the story.</li><li>I’m real bad at sharing what I do write. (The AI that scans all Google Drive documents for ad ideas is my #1 fan). </li></ul><p>So the idea of this blog is to remove the things I’m good at with creative writing (pretty much just planning), in order to focus on improving my weaknesses.</p><h3 id="Format"><a href="#Format" class="headerlink" title="Format"></a>Format</h3><p>Once a week, on Tuesdays, I will post a segment of a story to this blog. Over the course of the next few days, until Friday, you will have the chance to read the new post, comment what you think should happen next, and vote on other reader’s comments with which you agree. On Friday evening I will accept the comment with the most votes as the prompt for the next segment of the story. If there is a tie for top suggestion I will break the tie by picking my favorite.</p><p>When you feel like your suggestion should be the end of the story, say so in your comment. If a ending suggestion is accepted the story will end with the accompanying post.</p><p>I still intend to keep doing the occasional story challenge with my brother. To keep me honest, I will be posting those stories here under the “Story Challenge” category of this blog.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog! My name is Jonathan. The purpose of this blog is for me to get some practice with creative writing, and for you to (hopefully) get some entertainment out of it. Please read the rest of this post to get the backround on why this blog exists, and how it will operate. Or if that sounds boring to you I’ve provided this handy tl;dr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;TL-DR&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#TL-DR&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;TL;DR&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the latest post of the blog, which will be on the home page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vote in the comments on what should happen next.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat one week later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes there will be a bonus story that my brother made me write.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stories will be organized by category.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Beginning" scheme="https://JonHolt.github.io/categories/Beginning/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
